<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Soham's 2 cents</title>
    <description>A collection of short pieces of text</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 22:47:59 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 22:47:59 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.5</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Judo</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Being the first child in the family has its benefits and drawbacks. My parents got me enrolled in all possible classes, from improving vocabulary to table tennis and chess. Reading my blogs would have made you realise that most of them were not really useful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I never planned on getting coached in judo. It started when I was 6, practising roller skating at a local club. While I was at it, I was fascinated with other kids practising judo at the same club and spent a lot of time watching them. Seeing my interest in the sport, my parents got me enrolled in the judo class. For a 6-year-old, judo was just about going to class regularly and winning medals at competitions. This went on for a few years when I realised that this constant training had shaped my personality. I must have been 14 or 15 years old when I started seeing the benefits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing it taught me was to respect everyone. It doesn’t matter if that person is your coach, or someone younger to you, or your opponent, or what the person does outside the dojo (the area where judo is practised). Everyone works equally hard and so each person commands equal respect. To show this respect, all sorts of judo practices begin and end with a rei (bow as a mark of respect). I believe that I have been able to carry this idea and apply it to my everyday life as well. If you feel I haven’t, let me know in the comments below (Yeah, that’s one way to get more comments)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving on to the next judo lesson.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I fear not the man who has practised 10,000 kicks once, but I fear
the man who has practised one kick 10,000 times&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of you might know that Bruce lee said this. I completely agree with this. To execute one move perfectly in a tournament, it has to be practised thousands of times. My coach used all means to ensure that I got this into my mind at a very young age. After the first few years, it had become completely normal to have a set training routine for months to get a gold medal at a tournament. Standing on the podium with that medal around my neck made all that practice worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, after practising for almost 16 years, judo has become a part of my life. It’s something I can never completely detach from. Despite not being able to practice actively, I am trying to stay in touch with the sport as much as I can. I started assisting my coach in teaching kids who joined the club. Now I understand what teachers have to go through to get a children (less than 12 years of age) to listen to them and I don’t blame them any more for losing their temper or sending students to the principal’s office just to get them out of the class. But teaching kids does have it’s benefits. Watching them win medals at competitions has made me feel more fulfilled than ever before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One last thing that judo taught me was&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It’s not over till it’s over&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A fight/bout in Judo lasts for 5 minutes. Even if the opponent is leading (has an advantage in terms of points gained) throughout those 5 minutes, it just takes one perfectly executed move to win the fight. At the same time, you cannot afford to get complacent and lose focus if you have an advantage. By being in such situations numerous times, the one thing that I have understood is that nothing is permanent and it takes only one moment for the tides to turn&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/judo/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/judo/</guid>
        
        <category>judo</category>
        
        <category>martial-art</category>
        
        
        <category>Experience</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Quarantine</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Here is a post about the reason I started writing in the first place…. Quarantine. Before staying at home became a lifestyle, things were different. Playing cricket on weekends and driving half an hour to have vada pav in LA was normal. For me, things changed the day my university shut the gym. I had completed my shift at the bookstore and was on my way to the gym when I saw that the gym had shut and that too for an indefinite period of time. The next day it was declared that classes would be conducted online. It never got better from that point. My roommates and I had to cancel our trip to Arizona. Cricket on weekends was totally out of question now. &lt;em&gt;Normal&lt;/em&gt; was was going to be different now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing my roommates and I did was panic buying of toilet paper (Because, in the west, nothing is more important than toilet paper) and frozen food from the supermarket. We stocked up the refrigerator and the kitchen cabinets with all sorts of eatables. The university had shut down all facilities, so no more on-campus jobs. Deep down I felt relieved that I would have to stay at home all the time and have very limited social interaction. The first few days were very relaxing. We did was everyone around the world was doing during this period, made &lt;em&gt;Dalgona&lt;/em&gt; coffee, baked cakes, and played board games. Eventually, we got &lt;em&gt;bored&lt;/em&gt; of playing &lt;em&gt;board&lt;/em&gt; games…I agree that was poor wordplay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a few days, it got really monotonous. The only productive part of the day was working on homework assignments. For someone who tries to keep himself busy all the time, this situation left me completely stumped. Since this lockdown wasn’t going to end anytime soon, I had to find something to keep myself occupied. The first thing I started with was practising mindfulness.
I started with a 14-day mindfulness exercises course and followed it up with atleast 15 minutes of meditation every day. If you think that keeping your mind empty and thinking about &lt;em&gt;nothing&lt;/em&gt; is easy, it is not! My aim was to meditate every day and make it a part of daily routine. With so much free time at hand, meditation has really helped me prevent overthinking. It’s been over 2 months and I can safely say that I have not skipped a single day so far. The next thing I did during this lockdown was to start exercising at home. I got myself to take up the 100 push-ups per day challenge to ensure that I exercised every day. For the first few days, it is difficult to do the same thing over and over again. But after a while, it becomes a habit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peer pressure is worse when it’s via social media, that too when your LinkedIn feed has more activity than Facebook and Instagram combined. Every other person is either baking, working out, or doing online courses to learn something new. Since my friend started learning guitar, I wanted to do it too (No! I wouldn’t jump off a cliff if my friend jumped off a cliff), and I was never going to have more free time at hand than I had right now. About 3 weeks ago, I finally got myself to order a guitar and start with an online course. The last thing to check off the Todo list before kicking off with my internship was to start a personal blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that it’s been over a week into the internship, I feel much more relaxed. I have realised that what I was really missing during this period was constant routine. Waking up every morning and not having a fixed set of things to do was making me restless.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/quarantine/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/quarantine/</guid>
        
        <category>thoughts</category>
        
        <category>lockdown</category>
        
        <category>quarantine</category>
        
        
        <category>Experience</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Listen...</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;After a couple of years of contemplating, this is the first time I have actually tried to pen down my thoughts. Because what else would you do with all those thoughts in your head during this quarantine? For someone to whom writing doesn’t come naturally (you’ll see as you read along), writing this post with close to 500 words has been a monstrous task. The main reason for choosing this topic for the first post is that it is something I am able to relate to very deeply. So deeply that I have got it tattooed on my forearm. So here we go…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a world where everyone is busy pushing their opinions forward, we have left our ability to listen far, far behind. We do hear, we hear the words falling on our eardrums while we are busy coming up with more words to put forth our point of view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an introvert, (that’s what I like to call myself, though some of my friends may not agree with it entirely) I have never been particularly comfortable in social situations. While it’s difficult for me to greet people with a ‘Hi’ or ‘Hello’, small talk is totally off the table. When it comes to being in large groups, I often try to be the silent spectator who isn’t noticed that often so that I don’t have to speak much or answer questions. But, these social gatherings have always given me a chance to observe and listen to people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Closely listening to someone stating their beliefs and observing them react to normal situations provides a lot of insight into their way of thinking. Being a good-ish listener often helps me escape awkward social situations. I have realised that asking the right questions, coming up with timely acknowledgements and showing a slight bit of interest in what someone else is speaking works wonders for me. It makes people think I’m really interested in what they are saying. Though I have faked having an interest at times (when someone goes on boasting about their achievements), on most occasions I did get to know a lot about a person. Patiently watching them talk about their passion, experiences, likes, and dislikes with that sparkle in their eye reveals a lot about their nature and personality. It made me apprehend the fact that there is so much each of us has to share and all we are looking for is someone who would just listen to us with interest and without any judgement. After using this listening skill as an escape all this while, I have understood how important and underrated it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I continue to observe and listen to find more content for future posts, I hope this one doesn’t end up being the first and last one I write.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/listen/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/listen/</guid>
        
        <category>thoughts</category>
        
        
        <category>Listen</category>
        
        <category>Abstract</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
